Inventory of the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace. Domestic Studies Program working papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- 1992
  - Compensation, Productivity and the New Economics of Personnel, Edward P. Lazear, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Coordination Economies, Advertising and Search Behavior in Retail Markets, Kyle Bagwell and Garey Ramey, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Custom Versus Fashion: Path-Dependence and Limit cycles in a Random Matching Game, Kiminori Matsuyama, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Determinates of U.S. Labor Disputes, Peter C. Cramton and Joseph S. Tracy, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Disaggregate Evidence on the Substitutability Between Public and Private Spending, Michael Kuehlwein, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Do People Behave According to Bellman's Principle of Optimality?, John Rust, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Dual Method of Corporate Profits Distribution in France: An Empirical and Clinical Study 1983-1991, Bertrand Jacquillat, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Effect of Public Policies on Recent Swedish Fertility Behavior, John R. Walker, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Efficiency and the Non-Enforcement of Penalties, Charles Kolstad and Jim Leitzel, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Health Care Reform: Defining Rights, Setting Limits, and Paying Off the Bill, Alan F. Kremen, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Imperfect Competition, Foreign Trade, and the Multipliers: Machlup-Metzler Fifty Years Later, Kiminori Matsuyama, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Institutional Behavior of Japanese Commercial Banks-An Empirical Perspective, Ju-ichi Yamanaka, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Making Monopolistic Competition More Useful, Kiminori Matsuyama, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Market Size, Entrepreneurship, and the Big Push, Kiminori Matsuyama, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Planned and Unplanned Transfers Among the Affluent, Michael Kuehlwein, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Projection Methods for Solving Aggregate Growth Models, Kenneth L. Judd, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Public Goods in Trade: On the Formation of Markets and Political Jurisdictions, Alessandra Casella and Jonathan S. Feinstein, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Public Goods in Trade: On the Formation of Markets and Political Jurisdictions, Alessandra Casella and Johnathan S. Feinstein, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Some Thoughts on Savings, Edward P. Lazear, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Sources of Political Correctness on American Campuses, Seymour Martin Lipset, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Stacking the Senate, Changing the Nation: Republican Rotten boroughs, Statehood Politics, and American Political Development, Charles Stewart III and Barry R. Weingast, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Start-up Costs and Pecuniary Externalities as barriers to Economic Development, Antonio Ciccone and Kiminori Matsuyama, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Toward a Theory of International Currency, Kiminori Matsuyama, Nobuhiro Kiyotaki, and Akihiko Matsui, 1992 (Box 6)
- 1993
  - Computing Equilibria on the GEI Model, Donald J. Brown, Peter M. DeMarzo and B. Curtis Eaves, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Incentives in a Research Environment, Edward P. Lazear, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Industrial Research During the 1980s: Did the Rate of Return Fall?, Bronwyn H. Hall, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Innovation, Imitation, Technology Differentiation, and the Value of Information in New Markets, Debra J. Aron, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Medical Care in the United States: An Analysis of the Current System and a Proposal, Rita Ricardo-Campbell, James A. Albright and Eugene E. Bleck, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Nucleation of the Private Competitive Sector and Dissipation of the State Sector During Transition from a Socialist to a Market Economy, Ilya M. Fishman and Michael S. Berstam, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Overinvesting in Relationship-Specific Information under Short-Term Contracting, Gillian K. Hadfield, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Productivity and the Density of Economic Activity, Antonio Ciccone and Robert E. Hall, 1993 (Box 7)
  - R&D Tax Policy During the Eighties: Success or Failure?, Bronwyn H. Hall, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Transition in the Institutional Behavior of U.S. Commercial Banks-A Comparative Perspective, Ju-ichi Yamanaka, 1993 (Box 7)
- 1994
  - Bait-and Switch, Edward P. Lazear, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Cities and Skills, Edward L. Glaeser and David C. Mare, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Economic Growth and Urban Density: A Review Essay, Edward L. Glaeser, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Fiscal Effects of Direct Legislation: Evidence from the Last 30 Years, John G. Matsusaka, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Incentive Effects of Property Taxes on Local Governments, Edward L. Glaeser, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Intertemporal Allocation of Consumption: Theory and Evidence, Orazio P. Attanasio, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Is Consumption Growth Consistent with Intertemporal Optimization? Evidence from the Consumer Expenditure Survey, Orazio P. Attanasio and Guglielmo Weber, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Managerial Compensation, Control and Investment, Sherwin Rosen, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Neither a Borrower Nor Lender be: An Economic Analysis of Interest Restrictions and Usury Laws, Edward L. Glaeser and Jose A. Scheinkman, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Relative Wage Movements and the Distribution of Consumption, Orazio P. Attanasio and Steven J. Davis, 1994 (Box 8)
  - Theory of the Diversified Firm, Refocusing, and Divestiture, John G. Matsusaka and Vikram Nanda, 1994 (Box 9)
- 1995
  - Are Ghettos Good or Bad?, David M. Cutler and Edward L. Glaeser, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Assortative Marriage and the Dynamics of Inequality, Michael Kremer, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Capitalism and the Ethic of Care: New Directions for Policy, Philosophy, and Leadership, Alan F. Kremen, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Crime and Social Interactions, Edward L. Glaeser, Bruce Sacerdote and Jose A. Scheinkman, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Demand for Environmental Goods: Evidence from Voting Patterns on California Initiatives, Matthew E. Kahn and John G. Matsusaka, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Economic Growth in a Cross-Section of Cities, Edward L. Glaeser, Jose A. Scheinkman and Andrei Shleifer, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Integrating Behavioral Choice into Epidemiological Models of AIDS, Michael Kremer, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Optimal Tax on Capital Income is Negative, Kenneth L. Judd, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Segregation by Skill and the Rise of Inequality, Michael Kremer and Eric Maskin, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Should Transfer Payments be Indexed to Local Price Levels?, Edward L. Glaeser, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Transition to Free Markets: Where to Begin Privatization, Edward L. Glaeser and Jose A. Scheinkman, 1995 (Box 9)
- 1996
  - Access, Utilization, and Equity in Canada and the U.S.: An Empirical Model of Physician Visits, Barton H. Hamilton, Vivian H. Hamilton, and Harry J. Paarsch, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Approximating the First-Best in Agency Models with Step Function Contracts, Holger M. Mller, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Differences in Earnings and Wage Distributions between Canada and the United States: An Application of a Semi-Parametric Estimator of Distribution Functions with Covariates, Stephen G. Donald, David A. Green, and Harry J. Paarsch, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Health and Amenity Effects of Global Warming, Thomas G. Moore, 1996 (Box 9)
  - Randomization in Dynamic Principal-Agent Problems, Holger M. Mller, 1996 (Box 9)
- 1997
  - Interdealer Trading: Evidence from London, Peter C. Reiss and Ingrid M. Werner, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Pricing of Human Capital and Financial Assets, Ignacio Palacios-Huerta, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Reformulation of Utility Theory or It All Comes from Sex, Thomas G. Moore, 1997 (Box 9)
- 1998
  - Economic Recovery from the Argentine Great Depression: Institutions, Expectations, and the Change of Macroeconomic Regime, Gerardo della Paolera and Alan M. Taylor, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Essay on the Competitive Formation of Preferences, Ignacio Palacios-Huerta and Jesus J. Santos, 1998 (Box 9)
  - European Monetary Union: Initial Situation, Alternatives, Prospects-In the Light Modern Institutional Economics, Rudolph Richter, 1998 (Box 9)
  - Latin America and Foreign Capital in the Twentieth century: Economies, Politics, and Institutional Change, Alan M. Taylor, 1998 (Box 9)
- 2000
  - Macroeconomics from the Viewpoint of Modern Institutional Economics, Rudolph Richter, 2000 (Box 10)
- 2001
  - Increasing Wealth and Increasing Instability: The Role of Collateral, Charles Ka Yui Leung and Chung Yi Tse, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Productivity Growth, Increasing Income Inequality and Social Insurance: The Case of China?, Charles Ka Yui Leung, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Relating International Trade to the Housing Market: The Case of Tariff, Charles Ka Yui Leung, 2001 (Box 10)